Guide to the The University of Montana Department of Native American Studies Records 1921-2003
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana--Missoula
The University of Montana Department of Native American Studies Records
1921-2003
University of Montana, Mansfield Library, Archives and Special Collections The University of Montana, Missoula Missoula, MT 59812 406-243-2053 http://www.lib.umt.edu/asc library.archives@umontana.edu
RG 85
University of Montana. Department of Native American Studies
12.5 linear feet
The collection from the Department of Native American Studies contains material related to Native American organizations, legislation, tribes, education and the Native American Studies program at The University of Montana-Missoula.
Historical Note
The Native American Studies (NAS) Program began in the summer of 1970. It was founded with the intention “to promote better understanding between the native peoples of this country and all peoples,” and to “develop and foster understanding and acceptance of the Indian/Non-Indian relationships.” Henrietta Whiteman was the first full time program director. NAS supports community and university Native American projects and organizations, such as the Native American Cultural Institute, the Qua Qui and the Missoula Indian Alcohol and Drug Services, Upward Bound, the Kyi-Yo Indian Club, and the Indian Law Clinic.
In March 1999, the State Board of Regents voted to change Native American Studies from program status to department status. NAS graduated its first majors as a Department in May 1999, though it had graduated majors the previous three years as a program.
This collection primarily consists of subject files collected by the department and related to Native American organizations, legislation, tribes, education and the Native American Studies program at the University of Montana. The legislative information and acts pertain to Native American public education and social welfare. Included in the collection papers are university publications, course handouts, elementary and high school workshop and lesson plans, curriculums and philosophies of Native American education. Non-educational material consists of information on Native American languages, bibliographies, information and lectures from conferences and symposiums, and academic and informal papers addressing Native American empowerment. Also included is information pertaining to higher education such as graduate and professional program papers, program proposals, information particularly for Native Americans in other career fields, and NAS programs at other universities. Most material dates from 1962 to 1997.
The collection is divided into two series:
Series I: Subject Files, 11.5 linear ft., 1921-2003
Subseries 1: Organizations
Subseries 2: Government / Legislation
Subseries 3: Tribes
Subseries 4: Education
Subseries 5: Miscellaneous
Series II: Department Records, 1 linear ft., 1977-1997
Researchers must use collection in accordance with the policies of Archives and Special Collections, the Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, and The University of Montana--Missoula.
The bulk of this collection was transferred to the Archives by the Native American Studies Department in June of 2004.Several items were also transferred int he summer of 2013.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
University of Montana--Missoula. Native American Studies Program; University of Montana (Missoula, Mont.). Native American Studies Program
Indians of North America--Services for--Montana--Missoula; Indians of North America--Study and teaching (Higher)--Montana --Missoula
Montana; Colleges and Universities; Native Americans
- Subject Files, 1921-2003; Series I; 11.5 linear feet
  - Organizations, Subseries 1
    - American Indian Institute, Discussion paper concerning the Shared Goals of the American Indian Institute and the Montana University System, 1975 (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Aboriginal Cornucopia, lists of books on N.A.I. [Native American Institute] and regulations of Indian Dancing, 1921 and undated (Box-folder 1/2)
    - Address to School Administrators by Dorrance Steele, address N.A. I. to meet needs, 1974 (Box-folder 1/3)
    - Indian Student Leadership Conference, 1969 (Box-folder 1/15)
    - National Science Teachers Association, Energy: Soft heard, undated (Box-folder 2/32)
    - National Indian Education Association, 1976 (Box-folder 5/31)
    - National Education Association Memorandum, 1976 (Box-folder 5/40)
    - MUIA By-Laws, undated (Box-folder 6/41)
    - University of Montana Native American Studies Program, 1977 (Box-folder 6/44)
    - A.I.M [The American Indian Movement], undated (Box-folder 6/46)
    - NCAI [National Congress of American Indians], 1975 and undated (Box-folder 7/2)
    - NIEA [National Indian Education Association], 28th Annual Call to Convention, 1997 (Box-folder 7/15)
    - 4th Annual Tribal Higher Education Contractors, 1989 (Box-folder 11/33)
    - Montana Alliance for Progressive Policy, 1991 (Box-folder 12/9)
    - MIEA (Montana Indian Education Association), 1991 (Box-folder 12/10)
    - MIEA (Montana Indian Education Association), 1992 (Box-folder 12/11)
    - Eighth Annual Kyi-yo Conference Welcome Address, 1976 (Box-folder 12/18)
    - Senator Edward Kennedy Kyi-yo Conference, 1970 (Box-folder 12/19)
    - XLI International Congress of Americanists, 1974 (Box-folder 13/1)
    - First Annual Kyi-yo Health Club Conference Welcome Address, 1974 (Box-folder 13/2)
    - Native American Cultural Institute, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 14/15)
    - NACI (Native American Cultural Institute) Final Report, 1975 (Box-folder 14/20)
    - AADSAS (American Association of Dental Schools Application Services) Information and Application, 1977 (Box-folder 17/3)
    - Public Health Service Act, 90th Congress HR 6418, 1967 (Box-folder 19/3)
    - Public Health Service Act, 89thCongress, 1966 (Box-folder 19/4)
    - WAMI (Washington, Alaska, Montana, and Idaho) Program, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 19/9)
    - Native American Cultural Institute, Establishment of goals and Objectives for Indian Education, undated (Box-folder 19/12)
    - Hill Foundation, Documentation for Faculty Senate Committee, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 19/13)
    - Public Law 95-608, Indian Child Welfare Act, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 23/1)
    - Indian Child Welfare Act, 1977 (Box-folder 23/3)
    - International Congress of Americanists, 1975 (Box-folder 23/6)
    - North American Indian Conference on Aging, 1975 and 1977 (Box-folder 23/7)
    - Sights for Already Sore Eyes From the newspaper ABC (Americans Before Columbus), undated (Box-folder 23/29)
    - Sovereign Native Women's Conference, undated (Box-folder 23/32)
    - NAACP Report on Minority Testing, 1976 (Box-folder 23/39)
    - International NGO Conference on Discrimination Against Indigenous Populations in America's, 1977 (Box-folder 23/40)
    - NACI (National American Cultural Institute) Final Report, 1975 (Box-folder 24/21)
    - Community Crime Prevention Task Force, 1974 (Box-folder 24/22)
    - National Congress of American Indians, 1959 (Box-folder 24/31)
    - League of Indigenous Sovereign Nations, 1992 (Box-folder 25/3)
    - Amnesty International Human Rights and American Indians, 1992 (Box-folder 25/29)
    - National Conference of Christians and Jews, 1991 (Box-folder 25/30)
    - Winds of Changes, AISES (American Indian Science and Engineering Society) 14th Annual Conference Edition, 1992 (Box-folder 25/33)
  - Government/Legislation, Subseries 2
    - Billings Area Statistics, 1973 (Box-folder 2/25)
    - Cabin Creek Proposal, 1975 (Box-folder 2/26)
    - Capital Requirements in Western States, 1975 (Box-folder 2/27)
    - Coal Lease Lawsuits, 1975 and undated (Box-folder 2/28)
    - East Poplar River Memorandum, 1975 (Box-folder 2/29)
    - Indian Water Rights Vs. District Court Memorandum, 1971 (Box-folder 3/12)
    - International Joint Commission, U.S. and Canada Annual Report, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 3/13)
    - Indian Extension Land use statewide, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 3/14)
    - Montana Supplements to the School Laws, 1972 (Box-folder 4/12)
    - House of Representatives Education Committee, 44th session, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 4/16)
    - American Indian Religious Freedom, Laws of the 95th Congress, 1978 and 1979 (Box-folder 4/17)
    - The Bilingual Act Education Amendments of 1978, 1979 (Box-folder 4/24)
    - U.S. Census, As it Relates to the Native American Region 8, 1974 (Box-folder 4/31)
    - Evaluation Sheet for USOE/Office of Indian Education Part b. title 4, undated (Box-folder 5/6)
    - From the Children's Foundation-on the new School lunch law, undated (Box-folder 5/7)
    - Federal Funding File, Health and Rehabilitation Services, undated (Box-folder 5/8)
    - Federal Impact Aid 874 Education, undated (Box-folder 5/9)
    - Federal Laws which authorize assistance, 1917-1966 (Box-folder 5/10)
    - Forms to be used in developing a Federal program, undated (Box-folder 5/12)
    - The Indian Education Act 1972, 1976 (Box-folder 5/18)
    - HEW Indian Education Act, Part C, 1977 (Box-folder 5/21)
    - Indian Self- Determination and education Assistance Act, 1975 and undated (Box-folder 5/25)
    - Indian Studies Guidelines Title IV of Civil Rights Act, undated (Box-folder 5/26)
    - Indian Self-Determination Assistance Act, Pl 93-638, 1975 (Box-folder 5/27)
    - Montana, Supplements to the School Law, 1973 (Box-folder 5/39)
    - Policy On Indian Education, Joint and Concurrent Resolution, 1967-1971 (Box-folder 6/1)
    - Indian Studies, Board of Public Education in Montana, 1973-2003 (Box-folder 6/2)
    - Public Law 81-815, "School Facilities Construction Act", 1950 (Box-folder 6/6)
    - House Concurrent Resolution 108, 1961 and undated (Box-folder 11/1)
    - Bureau of the Census Statistical Brief, 1995 (Box-folder 11/14)
    - Title IX Indian Education, Missoulian Article, 1997 (Box-folder 11/15)
    - Article 97, Fee Waiver Works, 1997 (Box-folder 11/16)
    - Article 97, Sales Tax on Indian Land Protest, 1997 (Box-folder 11/18)
    - Article 97, Native Am Students Need Culture, 1997 (Box-folder 11/19)
    - Testimony presented to the House of Representatives at Missoula by Joe McDonald, 1988 (Box-folder 11/36)
    - Title VII Education Personnel Training Grant, 1992 (Box-folder 12/1)
    - Statement of Senator James Abourezk, Review legislative Accomplishments & plans 95th Congress, undated (Box-folder 14/8)
    - Montana Code Title & Allocation Tables, Montana Legislative Council, 1975 (Box-folder 14/23)
    - Public Law 94-437 94th Congress S.522, Improving Services and Facilities of Federal Indian Health programs, 1976 (Box-folder 16/1)
    - Public Law 874, Titles I And III, 1970 (Box-folder 16/2)
    - Public Law 815, Construction of school facilities/areas affected by Federal Activities, 1970 (Box-folder 16/3)
    - Public Law 815, Summary of School Facilities Construction Act, 1950 (Box-folder 16/4)
    - Proposed Rules, Indian Elementary and Secondary School Assistance Act, HEW (Department of Health, Education and Welfare), 1973 (Box-folder 16/5)
    - Revised Codes of Montana, HJR 60, 1947 (Box-folder 16/6)
    - Wheeler Howard Act, 1934 (Box-folder 16/12)
    - Taxation of Indian's Income, 67-284 Revenue Ruling, 1967 (Box-folder 16/20)
    - Supreme Court of the United States, 1974 (Box-folder 16/21)
    - Title 1 for Indian Children Fact Sheet, undated (Box-folder 16/23)
    - Title III Elementary-Secondary Education Act Operation Understanding, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 16/24)
    - Title IV - Indian Education, 1950 (Box-folder 16/25)
    - Title IV - Part B, undated (Box-folder 16/26)
    - Title VII - Emergency School Aid, undated (Box-folder 16/27)
    - Title IX - Ethnic Heritage Program, undated (Box-folder 16/28)
    - Senate Joint Resolution 17, Article X, Montana State Constitution, 1974 (Box-folder 16/32)
    - Supplement to the Schools Laws of Montana, 1973 (Box-folder 16/33)
    - Public Law 93-580, American Indian Policy Review Commission, 1975 (Box-folder 23/9)
    - Revised Codes of Montana, 1947 (Box-folder 23/10)
    - Political Campaign Reporting Practices, undated (Box-folder 23/8)
    - State Commission on Local Government, 1975 (Box-folder 23/11)
    - Montana Rules and Regulations for Candidates and Political, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 23/12)
    - Public Law 94-437, Indian Health Care Improvement Act, 1976 (Box-folder 23/36)
    - Racism In America-How to combat it., US Commission on Civil Rights, 1970 (Box-folder 23/37)
    - Civil Rights, Montana Commission Workshop - Title 4, Indian Education Act, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 24/7)
    - Civil Rights Update, Commission Calls for Extending and Strengthening Voting Rights, 1981 (Box-folder 24/8)
    - House Bill 343, Requiring American Indian Studies to be part of Public, 1973 (Box-folder 24/11)
    - Indian Culture Master Plan, House Joint Resolution 60 - House Bill 343, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 24/12)
    - Indian Studies Law Criteria, Indian Education Act, 1972 (Box-folder 24/13)
    - LC2294- Legislative Assembly, undated (Box-folder 24/18)
    - Correspondence, Legislative Alternative Recommendations for Committee consideration, 1973-1976 (Box-folder 24/23)
    - Affirmative Action Officers, Human Rights Bureau, 1976 (Box-folder 24/9)
    - Economic Development for Indians Committee, US Congress, 1970 (Box-folder 24/25)
    - House Joint Resolution 60, Montana, 1972 (Box-folder 24/27)
    - Revised Codes of Montana, 1947 (Box-folder 25/11)
    - Religious Freedom and the Protection of Native American Places of Worship and Cemeteries, 1977 (Box-folder 25/25)
  - Tribes, Subseries 3
    - Band Analysis System of Budget and funding, Tribal Priorities given, undated (Box-folder 1/5)
    - Houses of Native Americans, A Proposal, undated (Box-folder 1/14)
    - Confederated Salish and Kootenai tribes, 1974 (Box-folder 1/16)
    - Constitution and Bylaws of the Flathead Reservation, 1936, 1960 and undated (Box-folder 1/17)
    - Salish and Kootenai Tribal Constitution, 1935-1960 and undated (Box-folder 1/19)
    - Constitution and Bylaws of the Assiniboine and Sioux Tribes at Fort Peck Reservation, undated (Box-folder 1/20)
    - Constitution of the Crow Tribal Council, 1966 (Box-folder 1/21)
    - Plant Taxonomy Salish & Kootenai, 1971 (Box-folder 1/22)
    - Flathead Reservation, Montana, undated (Box-folder 1/23)
    - Blackfeet Language Survey, 1979 (Box-folder 1/25)
    - Blackfeet Tribe Constitution and Information, 1887-1968 and undated (Box-folder 1/26)
    - California Indians Biography, 1962 (Box-folder 1/27)
    - Constiution and Bylaws of the Fort Belknap Reservation, 1935-1976 (Box-folder 2/1)
    - Rocky Boy's Arrow and Spike Association, Inc., 1980 (Box-folder 2/2)
    - Rosebud Indian Reservation transitional Housing Experiment Report, 1968 (Box-folder 2/3)
    - Chippewa Cree Tribe (lesson plan), 1981 and undated (Box-folder 2/4)
    - Chippewa Cree, Lifecycle (lesson plan), undated (Box-folder 2/5)
    - Chippewa Cree, the Tipi (lesson plan), undated (Box-folder 2/6)
    - Chippewa Cree, Economy, animal uses (lesson plan), undated (Box-folder 2/7)
    - Chippewa Cree, Social Sciences concepts and values (lesson plan), undated (Box-folder 2/8)
    - Chippewa Cree, Syllabic Characters, undated (Box-folder 2/9)
    - Chippewa Cree, Manufacturing (lesson plan), undated (Box-folder 2/10)
    - Chippewa Cree, transportation (lesson plan), undated (Box-folder 2/11)
    - Chippewa Cree, food (lesson plan), undated (Box-folder 2/12)
    - Chippewa Cree, Clothing (lesson plan), undated (Box-folder 2/13)
    - Kiowa, Booklet, undated (Box-folder 2/14)
    - Tribal Constitution Northern Cheyenne Research Project, 1977 (Box-folder 2/15)
    - Northern Cheyenne Tribal Constitution, 1934-1977 (Box-folder 2/16)
    - Northern Cheyenne Follow Through Project, undated (Box-folder 2/17)
    - Corporate Charter of Northern Cheyenne Tongue River Reservation, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 2/18)
    - The Rocky Boy Reservation, 1974 (Box-folder 2/19)
    - The Southern Cheyenne, Booklet, undated (Box-folder 2/20)
    - Assiniboine and Sioux Constitution and Bylaws, 1974 and undated (Box-folder 2/21)
    - Menominee Restoration Act Rectify the Effect of Termination, 1972-1975 and undated (Box-folder 2/22)
    - Crow Reservation Energy Development, 1977 (Box-folder 2/30)
    - Crow Reservation Coal Lease, undated (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Federal Coal Strip Act, Crow Tribe Taxation Code, 1975 and undated (Box-folder 3/5)
    - Flathead Drainage 208 Project, 1975 (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Rocky Boy's Reservation- Tribal Government School Dist. #87, 1973 (Box-folder 4/6)
    - Browning People Create an Indian Free School, undated (Box-folder 5/3)
    - Tribal Law and Policy Institute, The Justice System and Indian Crime, 1997 (Box-folder 6/3)
    - Tribal Sovereignty Issues, Government to Government Relations with Indian Tribes, 1995 (Box-folder 6/4)
    - Cheyenne Language Lesson: Colors, undated (Box-folder 6/7)
    - Cheyenne Language Lesson: nouns, verbs, counting, undated (Box-folder 6/8)
    - Cheyenne Language Lesson: Lessons I-IV, undated (Box-folder 6/9)
    - Handbook to the Cheyenne Language, undated (Box-folder 6/10)
    - EESTSE-VOHOESTOTSE Vehestotse, Northern Cheyenne Bilingual Education Program, undated (Box-folder 6/11)
    - Holy Stories of the Cheyenne, Legend of Sweet Medicine, undated (Box-folder 6/12)
    - Words of Hiamovi, High Chief, undated (Box-folder 6/13)
    - The First White Man, undated (Box-folder 6/14)
    - Aspects of Culture, undated (Box-folder 6/15)
    - Cheyenne Circle of Knowledge, undated (Box-folder 6/16)
    - Cheyenne, Early Childhood Teachings, undated (Box-folder 6/17)
    - Suggested Essay Topics, Cheyenne Language & Culture, undated (Box-folder 6/18)
    - Criteria Determining Cheyenne Tribal Identity, undated (Box-folder 6/19)
    - Cheyenne Alphabet, undated (Box-folder 6/20)
    - The Soul of the Indian, undated (Box-folder 6/21)
    - Sacred Hat is Moved, undated (Box-folder 6/22)
    - Cheyenne Life Journey, undated (Box-folder 6/23)
    - Overview of Native American Tribes and Languages, undated (Box-folder 6/24)
    - Prayers in Cheyenne, undated (Box-folder 6/25)
    - Amended Constitution and By-Laws Northern of the Cheyenne Indian Reservation, undated (Box-folder 6/26)
    - Miscellaneous Handouts, How the stick game is played, undated (Box-folder 6/27)
    - Constitution and By-Laws Cheyenne-Arapaho Tribes of Oklahoma, undated (Box-folder 6/28)
    - White Wolfe, undated (Box-folder 6/29)
    - Cheyenne, Whoeniv-The Morning Star, undated (Box-folder 6/30)
    - Cheyenne Social Structure, undated (Box-folder 6/31)
    - Cheyenne Sounds, undated (Box-folder 6/32)
    - Amended Constitution, Northern Cheyenne, undated (Box-folder 6/33)
    - Map Showing the Indian Reservations in 1874, undated (Box-folder 6/34)
    - Map of Montana Indian Reservations, undated (Box-folder 6/35)
    - Northern Cheyenne, Reservation, undated (Box-folder 6/36)
    - Northern Cheyenne Reservation, Map, undated (Box-folder 6/37)
    - PAPEPOOH: The Cheyenne Alphabet, Vowels, Stops, Nasals, Fricatives, undated (Box-folder 6/38)
    - Pronunciation Guide, undated (Box-folder 6/39)
    - National Coalition to Support Indian Treaties, 1977, 1979 and undated (Box-folder 6/42)
    - Seattle Indian Center (Box-folder 6/43)
    - Fort Peck Reservation Information, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 7/16)
    - Recognized Tribal Entities, 1994 (Box-folder 7/20)
    - Do Bananas Telephone? Language processes of young Sioux children, undated (Box-folder 9/12)
    - The Canadian Indian Historical Information, undated (Box-folder 9/27)
    - Canada's Northern Frontier "Our Land, Our Life", Indian nation fights for survival on Canada's Northern frontier, undated (Box-folder 9/28)
    - Handgame of the Kiowa, Kiowa-Apache and Comanche, 1963 and undated (Box-folder 9/30)
    - Cultural Identity of the Indian and Eskimo People, Selected Speeches by Ministers of Indian Affairs, 1967 (Box-folder 10/1)
    - BlackFeet Reservation, undated (Box-folder 10/3)
    - The History of America Began With Us by Gran Tecolate of the Lenni Lenape Nation, undated (Box-folder 10/16)
    - History of Turtle Mountain Band/Chippewa Indians by Aun nish e naubay (Patrick Gourneau), undated (Box-folder 10/17)
    - Ka-Ka-Qwa-Pee-Wisk Memoirs, undated (Box-folder 10/19)
    - California Indian Population, Selected Social & Economic Characteristics, 1970 (Box-folder 10/23)
    - Task Force Hearing Little Shell Band of MT in Olympia, WA, 1976 (Box-folder 10/26)
    - Fort Belknap Reservation, Brief History, 1974 (Box-folder 10/27)
    - Map and historical information: Indian Reservations of Montana, undated (Box-folder 10/29)
    - A condensed History of the Navajo, Compiled by Carl H. Cords, undated (Box-folder 10/37)
    - Flathead Reservation History, 1996 (Box-folder 11/12)
    - Navajo Bilingual-Bicultural Curriculum, undated (Box-folder 11/28)
    - Commencement Address North Cheyenne Reservation, 1974 (Box-folder 13/4)
    - English-Dakota Dictionary, 1989 (Box-folder 14/10)
    - Edward Red Hat, Cheyenne Arrow Keeper, 1977 (Box-folder 14/13)
    - Northern and Southern Cheyenne Chiefs and Warrior Societies Conference, 1973 (Box-folder 14/14)
    - Resources About Specific Nations, undated (Box-folder 14/16)
    - Northern Cheyenne, "Indians, Coal & Big Sky", 1974 (Box-folder 14/25)
    - Cheyenne Prayer "The Lord's Prayer", 1983 (Box-folder 15/1)
    - Cheyenne Language prepared by Wayne Leman, Linguistics Experimental, 1975 (Box-folder 15/2)
    - Student Activists: the Navajo way By Stan Steiner July, 1969 (Box-folder 15/8)
    - Unit-Religion Chippewa Cree Title 4 Indian Education Program, undated (Box-folder 15/16)
    - Orientation to Montana Indian Tribes for the Indian Culture Master Plan, 1978 (Box-folder 15/17)
    - Blood Clot Boy Doings Written in Dakota by David Grey Cloud, undated (Box-folder 25/23)
    - Chief Seattle's Challenge, undated (Box-folder 25/24)
  - Education, Subseries 4
    - Contemporary Thought on Indian Education in South Dakota, 1973 (Box-folder 1/8)
    - History of Haskell Institute, undated (Box-folder 1/13)
    - Boarding School Eligibility, Bureau of Indian Affairs, 1975 (Box-folder 1/24)
    - University of Oklahoma Energy Institute, 1978 (Box-folder 2/31)
    - Montana's Involvement In the Johnson O'Malley Program, Current Conditions and Trends, 1974 (Box-folder 4/1)
    - Johnson O'Malley Program, 25 CFR Part 33, 1972 and 1974 (Box-folder 4/2)
    - Johnson O'Malley Program Johnson O'Malley Act and History, 1974 (Box-folder 4/3)
    - Johnson O'Malley Program Revision #10, Oct. 1, 1972 (Box-folder 4/4)
    - Johnson O'Malley Program, Title 25- Indians, 1974 (Box-folder 4/5)
    - The Law, Indians and Educations, 1972 (Box-folder 4/7)
    - Legislative Analysis of the Federal Role in Indian Education, 1975 (Box-folder 4/8)
    - Montana Indian Student Enrollment, 1975 and 1976 (Box-folder 4/9)
    - Standards for Accreditation of Teacher Education, Multicultural Education, 1979 (Box-folder 4/10)
    - Montana Educational Assessment Program, 1976 (Box-folder 4/11)
    - Montana Teacher Aides Comparison Survey Results, 1972 (Box-folder 4/13)
    - "No One Model American", an article on multicultural education, undated (Box-folder 4/14)
    - Indian Education by Raymond Carlisle, undated (Box-folder 4/15)
    - Fact sheet-BIA Special Education Line Item Appropriations, undated (Box-folder 4/18)
    - Rules and Regulations of U of S.D., undated (Box-folder 4/19)
    - American Indian Policy and Review Committee, Final Report Task Force #5 Indian Education, 1976 (Box-folder 4/20)